rainviewer.com 2019-05-16

# Privacy Policy - RainViewer

Thank you for using RainViewer. This privacy policy went into effect on September 28, 2018.

## 1\. INTRODUCTION

We appreciate that you trust us with your information and we intend to always keep that trust. This starts with making sure you understand the information we collect, why we collect it, how it is used and your choices regarding your information.

 _The company responsible for your information is:_  
P.E. Oleksii Schastlyvyi  
20 Tarasivska str., suite 85  
Kyiv, 01033  
Ukraine

## 2\. WHERE THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES

This Privacy Policy applies to our website, apps and other RainViewer services. We refer to all of these as our “services” or “apps” in this Privacy Policy.

## 3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We can’t help you have an awesome user experience without some information about you, such as your email address and location. We also collect information generated as you use our services, as well as information from third parties. Your information may be kept in an identifiable format, or in an aggregate format which means that you cannot reasonably be identified from it.

### Information you give us

You choose to give us certain information when using our services. This includes:

  * Email address and name when you subscribe to our newsletter.
  * If you contact our support team, we collect the information you give us when you report a problem, contact or communicate with us.
  * Information we receive from others.

In addition to the information you provide us directly, we receive information about you from others, including:

#### Our Partners

• We may receive information about you from our partners, for instance where our ads are published on a partner’s website or platform (in which case they may pass along details on a campaign’s success). • If you purchase a subscription in our apps, neither Google nor Apple provide us with any personal information of the subscription purchaser (like name, email or payment information). Only anonymized data gets passed to the RainViewer.

#### Information collected when you use our services

When you use our services, we collect information about which features you’ve used, how you’ve used them and the devices you use to access our services. See below for more details:

#### Usage Information

  * We collect information about your activity on our services, for instance how you use them (e.g., date and time you launched the app or visit website, time spent in the app, features you’ve been using, advertising that you click on).
  * Device information
  * We collect information from and about the device(s) you use to access our services, including:
  *     * Geolocation data, which is any information which indicates the geographical position of your device and which may include the time the location was recorded, and may include precise (e.g., GPS-level) location data. App may collect this data when the app is not open or actively in use. This may help us to build the forecast right for your location or help third parties to customize information, content, or offers to you, for instance.
  *     * Hardware and software information such as IP address, device ID and type, app crashes, app version, advertising IDs (such as Google’s Advertising ID and Apple’s IDFA, both of which are randomly generated numbers that you can reset by going into your device’s settings), browser type, version and language, operating system, time zones, identifiers associated with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your device or browser (e.g., IMEI/UDID and MAC address).

## 4\. COOKIES AND OTHER SIMILAR DATA COLLECTION TECHNOLOGIES

As described in Sections 3 and 5 of this Privacy Policy, we sometimes work with third parties to deliver ads or offers. Sometimes we or these third parties do so through a mobile “SDK.” We may use this and similar technology to deliver certain advertising through mobile applications and browsers based on data associated with your mobile device, and we may work with third parties who likewise embed their SDKs into our services, for third party advertising. If you’d like to opt-out from having ads tailored to you in this way on your mobile device, please follow the instructions below or in the app (as applicable).

If you wish to opt out of interest-based tracking through your mobile device, you can do so through your device “settings”, as follows (but please note that the below is for informational purposes only and Apple, Google, or other device platforms may change the manner in which their “opt out” settings work at any time): Please note that if you opt out through these settings, you will continue to receive advertising after you opt-out, but it may not be tailored to your interests. For instance, that advertising may be based on your real-time or “contextual” application usage or general location inferred from IP address.

 _Opting Out on iOS Devices Such as iPhones, iPads or iPods._  
If you have an Apple device, you can opt out of interest-based advertising by updating to iOS 6.0 or higher, and setting Limit Ad Tracking to ‘ON’. On an iPhone 6 for example, you can do this by clicking on Settings -> General -> Privacy -> Advertising and toggling “Limit Ad Tracking” to ‘ON’. Our systems are designed to respect your choice and not use your personal information to provide interest-based advertising when this setting is ON.

 _Opting Out on Android Devices._  
If you have an Android device and would like to opt out of interest-based advertising, you may do this as follows:

  * Open the Settings app on your device
  * Go to “Google”
  * Select Ads
  * Opt out of interest-based ads More information on our use of cookies on our websites can be found in our Cookie Policy.

## 5\. HOW WE USE INFORMATION

The main reason we use your information is to deliver and improve our services. Additionally, we use your info to communicate with you.

### To provide our services to you

  * Deliver our services to you and ensure their optimal functionality and operation.
  * Provide you with customer support and respond to your requests.
  * We use your email address, name, country and language for customized marketing purposes.
  * When we collect your precise geolocation data (subject to your consent) (which may be via the device’s cellular, Wi-Fi, Global Positioning System (GPS) networks and/or Bluetooth information), we do so to provide you with our location-related products and services, for example to provide you with forecast and weather alerts for your exact location, and also to facilitate, measure, or otherwise support advertising by third parties (through our apps or third parties’ apps) that may be related to your location over time.

### To improve our services and develop new ones

  * Develop new features and services (for example, we may decide to build a new feature further to requests or feedback received from users).
  * RainViewer uses the Google Analytics tool Firebase and the Google Analytics itself in order to carry out analysis on information which is gathered by our apps. Device information and other information which we gather are provided to Google in order to enable them to carry out data analysis. Any information which is provided to Google will become subject to Google’s privacy policy which is located here: www.google.com/privacy.html. For further information on how Google’s Firebase analytics tool uses data, please see the site “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps”, (located at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.
  * Conduct research and analysis of your behavior about your use of, or interest in, our products, services, or content to improve our services and content (for instance, we may decide to change the look and feel or even substantially modify a given feature based on users’ behavior). This software may record information such as how often you use the services, what happens within the services, aggregated usage, performance data, app errors and debugging information, and where the apps were downloaded from.

### To communicate with you

  * Communicate with you by email or mobile devices (including through in-application advertising) about products or services that may be of interest to you either from us, our parent or subsidiary companies or other third parties. If you do not wish to receive in-application advertising, you can upgrade to the paid version of the app.

### To serve you relevant offers and ads

  * Develop and display content and advertising (and work with third parties who do so) tailored to your interests and/or location and to measure its effectiveness. When you are on our services, third-party ad partners may provide you with advertising based upon your interests. These companies may use technologies to collect data about users, including precise device location data, to help them tailor relevant ads and measure ads’ effectiveness. These companies may collect this data through SDKs or from users who view or interact with their advertisements. For the purposes of European law, most of these ad partners are independent controllers of your information, which means that they are responsible for providing and complying with their own policies relating to any personal information they obtain in connection with the services. It also means that if you are a Facebook app user for example – you provided consent to Facebook in your Facebook app to allow them to show you personalized ads inside of our services.

### To ensure legal compliance

  * Comply with legal requirements
  * Assist law enforcement
  * Enforce or exercise our rights, for example our EULA

Since our goal is to provide the best services we can to you, the main sharing of users’ information is with service providers and partners who assist us in operating the services.

### With our service providers and partners

  * We follow a strict vetting process prior to engaging any service provider or working with any partner. We use third parties to help us operate and improve our services. These third parties assist us with various tasks, including data hosting and maintenance, analytics, marketing, advertising and security operations. These service providers may have limited access to your information, which is needed to perform their functions, but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes. We use your non-personal information (meaning information that, by itself, does not identify who you are such as device information) for targeted online marketing through tools like Facebook Custom Audience to contact interested parties.
  * In addition, we may share aggregated information we collect, under any of the above circumstances, with third parties, including advisors, advertisers and investors, for the purpose of conducting general business analysis or other legitimate business purposes. Please note that such aggregated information will not include any information which allows third parties to identity you.
  * We may transfer your information if we are involved, whether in whole or in part, in a merger, sale, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of ownership or control.
  * We may disclose your information if reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with a legal process, such as a court order, subpoena or search warrant, government / law enforcement investigation or other legal requirements; (ii) in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; or (iii) to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, our employees, or others.
  * We may also share information: (i) if disclosure would mitigate our liability in an actual or threatened lawsuit; (ii) as necessary to protect our legal rights and legal rights of our users, business partners or other interested parties and/or to comply with applicable law; (iii) to enforce our agreements or policies with you; and (iv) to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing.
  * We may ask for your consent to share your information with third parties. In any such case, we will make it clear why we want to share the information.

## 7\. HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after it is received. We work hard to protect you from unauthorized access to or alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information. As with all technology companies, although we take steps to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information will always remain secure. We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and regularly review our information collection, storage and processing practices to update our physical, technical and organizational security measures.

## 8\. YOUR RIGHTS

We want you to be in control of your information and be aware of your privacy rights, so here are a few key points to remember:

  * Depending on your location you may have some or all of the following rights in relation to how we use your personal information:
  *     * Access: you may request access to your personal information and receive copies of it;
  *     * Correction: you may have inaccurate/incomplete personal information corrected and updated;
  *     * Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: you can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal information or to limit our use of it.
  *     * Deletion: in certain circumstances, you can request a right “to be forgotten” (this is a right to have your information deleted or our use of your data restricted). We will honour such requests unless we have to retain this information to comply with a legal obligation or unless we have an overriding interest to retain it.
  *     * Portability: in certain circumstances, exercise the right to data portability (this is a right to obtain a transferable version of your personal information to transfer to another provider)
  *     * Consent Management: where we rely on consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw consent at any time. You do not have to provide a reason for your withdrawal where processing is based on consent.
  * If you wish to exercise any of these rights, or wish to object to our use of your information, please write to us at the address listed below and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.
  * Keep in mind, we may reject requests for certain reasons, including if the request is unlawful or if it may infringe on the rights and freedoms of another person. For example, we may not be able to accommodate certain requests to object to the processing of personal information, notably where such requests would not allow us to provide our service to you anymore.
  * For your protection, we may ask you to provide proof of identity before we can answer the above requests.

## 9\. CROSS-BORDER DATA TRANSFERS

Sharing of information sometimes involves cross-border data transfers, for instance to the United States of America and other jurisdictions. The United States, European Economic Area (“EEA”) Member States, and other countries all have different laws. When your information is moved from your home country to another country, the laws and rules that protect your personal information in the country to which your information is transferred may be different from those in the country in which you live.

The European Commission has adopted standard contractual clauses (also known as Model Clauses), which provide safeguards for personal information that is transferred outside of the EEA. We use these Model Clauses or other suitable safeguards (such as EU-US Privacy Shield to send personal information to some of our third party service providers in the United States, where they are certified to receive such information under the Privacy Shield Program) to permit data transfers from the EEA to other countries.

## 10\. HOW LONG WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION

We retain your information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this policy, for as long as needed to provide the services to you. We will also retain and use your information to the extent necessary:

  * to comply with applicable law;
  * to evidence our compliance with applicable law;
  * if there is an outstanding issue, claim or dispute requiring us to keep the relevant information until it is resolved; or
  * if the information must be kept for our legitimate business interests, such as enforcing our terms or fraud prevention. For example, information may need to be kept to prevent a user who was banned for security incidents from opening a new account.

Keep in mind that even though our systems are designed to carry out data deletion processes according to the above guidelines, we cannot promise that all data will be deleted within a specific timeframe due to technical constraints.

## 11\. PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

Because we’re always looking for new and innovative ways to help you enjoy our services, this policy may change over time. We will notify you of any material changes so that you have time to review the changes.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, here’s how you can reach us:

Online: [support@rainviewer.com](mailto:support@rainviewer.com)

By post:  
Oleksii Schastlyvyi  
20 Tarasivska str., apt. 85  
Kyiv, 01033  
Ukraine
